hey guys so which one of these is
greater 5 to the 100 or 3 to the 150. we
could probably just plug this into a
calculator I think it'd be more fun to
try this by hand without a calculator
upon first inspection 5 is greater than
three a one fifty is greater than 100 so
it's not immediately obvious which one's
greater I can fairly easily change this
5 into 25 and the 3 into a 27. so once
we do this it might be easier to compare
these so let's rewrite 5 to the power of
100 as 5 to the power of two times fifty
and let's rewrite 3 to the power of 150
as 3 to the power of three times fifty
and we can strategically place
parentheses here and here and so we can
see 5 squared is just 25 so this would
be to the 50 and 3 cubes is just 27 so
this would be to the 50. now we have 25
to the 50 compared to 27 to the 50. and
27 to the 50 will be the greater one so
this is the answer to the question how
exciting